blessings everyone this is Chris Kendall
from TheRawAdvantage.com registered
holistic nutritionist raw food lifestyle
coach and raw chef. Today I'm super
excited to share with you a raw pad thai
pad thai recipe as served at the Woodstock
fruit festival! Ohh baby I like it the raw
advantage likes it raw! Alright
guys I'm really excited to share this
recipe with you served a wide acclaim at
the Woodstock fruit festival last year
in fact if you guys haven't signed up
already or you've never gone to the
Woodstock fruit festival before you can
get a hundred bucks off with my code
"banana" if you've been there before you
know what's up, come enjoy it's gonna be
a blast! I'm so excited for it this year!
But again this recipe was served there
and I've wanted to share for quite a
while is taking me a little bit and I
wanted to offer a slight tweak for you, you
guys you're gonna get two options now
before we get into this recipe I do want
to share with you guys that I've just
launched the raw vegan lifestyle success
system it's up on my site and it's a
10-week online course with six live
group coaching calls and it's all
starting on the 1st of Feb so from the first
ten weeks on, now between now and
February 1st there's a special launch
beta price so you can get 20% off the
whole program for the first run but
don't worry you get access for life so I
really feel this is the absolute best
most streamlined way to learn how to
apply the raw vegan lifestyle in a
really successful easy way so whether
you're sick and tired of being sick and
tired you want to bring your athletics
the next level or you just really want
to understand this whole raw food
lifestyle from a holistic approach and
that's what it's all about so learn more
below or above! Let's jump right into
this recipe now the base of these
noodles are zucchini noodles, I love
zucchini noodles you could definitely
use cucumber noodles if you like or more
of the other noodles, we use zucchini
noodles. Now you have a lot of options
when you're making zucchini noodles my
favorite for this specific recipe is
actually the titan julienne peeler here
yes use it just like a regular peeler
but it makes beautiful flat noodles and
I'll just let you know I am an amazon
affiliate and I'm affiliate for some
other things so I'll have links below if
you want to grab some of these tools
that I absolutely love. So that's what I
used for this recipe otherwise of course
you could just use a grater you know you
could use a mandolin you can use any of
those things or you can use an electric
spiralizer this is a pretty epic one
thinkkitchen there's like 25 bucks and
then you can just put your zucchini in
there switch it on and then get doing
your sauce while you're doing other
stuff this works for a lot of thing but
again I like the thin black noodles that
are they're more pad thai ish so this
makes it a little bit more authentic
next we have some napa cabbage noodles
if you know what napa cabbage is it's
also known as Chinese cabbage it's
really nice and tender and delicious and
it's usually really inexpensive so we
just sliced that incredibly thinly into
noodles one of my favorite ways to make
noodles and we'll just add this to the
mix next we have beautiful bok choy one
of my absolute favorite greens as well
usually inexpensive soup or super
nutrient dense and we just slice that
thin into noodles as well we're gonna
add that on top
I also took a little bit of carrot and
use that same julienne peeler and just
made some nice little strands and last
but not least for this mixture we did a
little bit of red pepper matchsticks it
really bring a little bit of extra color
and just look and taste nice and juicy
now of course if you like you could add
anything else in there the Woodstock
fruit festival you actually had thinly
sliced shiitake mushrooms which are
delicious in there as well we had this
beautiful noodle base so we could just
mix this up and then we'll get to the
sauce
all right so getting into the sauce I
said I'd give you guys two versions and
you're lucky because I'm deliver it so
at the Woodstock fruit festival we have
an abundance of young coconuts tonnes
and sugarcane juice and so many other
amazing tropical fruits and vegetables
but you know back home here young
coconuts can be quite expensive and they
can be really hit and miss I do have one
your actually got a good deal on it but
that's a wood stock we used one cup of
coconut water to one half of a cup of
the young jelly the thinner young jelly
not the hard coconut meat so you just
chop this open pour the liquid in there
and then put
young coconut meat in there now today
I'm gonna give you another option
because again it's a little bit
expensive and sometimes hard to find
those in every single area so if you
haven't seen my video on the vitamix
versus the Flex ion vacuum blender
you're gonna want to check that out
above or below I used both a lot and I
do a really good versus video on that
but we're gonna use this one today and I
do like it quite a bit so we have the
beautiful blender and we're gonna start
by adding one cup of water instead of
the coconut water to replace that young
jelly we're gonna do 1/4 cup of hemp
seeds now these are lower water content
they cream up a lot more that's why it's
1/4 cup of this versus the half a cup of
the young coconut jello so quarter a cup
of hemp seeds here we have a hundred and
ten grams of dates now depending upon
the variety of dates you use it might be
like four medjool dates this is six of
these other soft varieties you want
pretty soft dates and make sure you pick
those the next really funny ingredient is
tamarind. Now this is what makes Pad Thai
Pad Thai ish it's very lemony and sour
but a really unique flavor in fact if
you can't find tamarind and it usually
comes in a block like this looking for
the sour tamarind rather than the sweet
you can also just replace it with about
two-thirds of the amount of apricots and
then a teaspoon of lime juice it'll give
you a similar flavor but this one from
that package it has some seeds in it
sometimes so I kind of squished and went
through it to try and make sure there
isn't any seeds because a seed although
there's a little bit here can kind of
wreck the dish when you she want
something hard so we're gonna throw that
tamarind in there next we have 20 grams
or about a quarter cup of sun-dried
tomatoes the bottoms of two green onions
reserving the tops 20 grams of fresh
ginger now I did to peel off a little
bit of the ball sackish looking bits but you
don't really need to have you have a
powerful blender like this or the
Vitamix just throw them right in there
and that's it we're gonna start with
this and blend it till some nice and
smooth so in the Flex ion you gotta
start the vacuum going we're gonna
put it on back in blend
so while that's going of course but
sweat off your brow
we dance
make pad thai tonight, you know whatever you want
to do but this guy's just sucking all
the air or the container right now so it
creates less oxidization and increases
the amount of antioxidant that is
left in the food and you're blending it
it really doesn't actually make a
different texture and taste I'm enjoying
it a lot but let's see how this does it
this is the first time I've actually
used this one on and if need be you can
add a little bit more water or you have
that coconut water and you can use the
coconut water
there because it's all done this is one
of my favorite things
suction cup to figure huh when you pull
this the air goes in there and you can
actually see the level change pretty
darn cool alright so now it's not quite
done what we're gonna do is add the
green onion tops as well as 20 grams of
cilantro
now cilantro isn't completely
traditional pad thai but I just love
cilantro so you can choose to leave that
out if you like this is one place where
the Vitamix reign supreme if this does
have a hard time blending then you have
the tamper you just push it in the blade
so to make sure that this goes in there
I'm gonna push this in there already and
hope that we get at least a decent pulse
so we're gonna put this back on and
because we're just doing a couple pulses
I'm not gonna bother vacuuming at this
time see this may be one of those
conditions is the Vitamix or who's a
better idea for
we go looks like it's mixing in there
pretty good all right and their weight
happened not full disclaimer the Vitamix
would have been better for this part of
the sauce
hey there Didi face how are you huh how
are you beautiful Kitty
this here is Didi face and she's a
really really good one. And there
you have it guys all we got to do now is
mix this over the noodles and you'll
notice that the sauce is incredibly
thick and I did that on purpose because
when you put sauces on top especially if
they've a little bit of sodium in it
with sun-dried tomatoes or you know
regular tomatoes or anything like that
it pulls the moisture out of the noodles
that's why your noodles get really
watery right so I made a really extra
thick so that when you put it on here
you stirred up some of the liquid from
the noodles will actually kind of merge
into the sauce and it'll meet the exact
right texture
use a spatula to the rest of this
out oh my god that is so damn good I
really really hope you guys loved this
recipe if you liked it or if you like
what I'm doing and all the other recipes
please give a thumbs up down below hit
the subscribe button and hit the bell
you will be notified when I put out new
videos I typically do one every single
with this raw vegan lifestyle success
system I might get a little bit patchy
over the next woxing I'm really really
busy with that helping as many people as
I possibly can and again if you're
looking to thrive on a truly holistic
raw vegan lifestyle then definitely
check out the raw vegan lifestyle
success system. Let's stir this up
yeah and there we have it guys raw vegan
Pad Thai super delicious super
nutritious really nice and authentic
flavor I hope you guys absolutely love
it make sure you comment below let me
know what you think wishing you much
peace love and seasonal fruit! Raw Pad Thai I hope you love it! oh don't forget
to check out my raw recipes playlist in
the top left the video just for you in
the top right subscribe for more videos
in the bottom right and here three free
ebooks in the bottom left! grab your free
raw recipe app available on iPhone and
Android with over 100 free raw recipes
food combining chart, fruit and vegetable calorie breakdown and so much more!
freaking awesome food to my shopping
cart functions so much more